Guide to the Robert Lynch papers, 1963-1989
Lynch, Robert papers, 1963-1989
- Series II. Writings
  - Shamanism, Berdache, and Homoeroticism in Amerindian Culture, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Outside Art From A Critical And Collector's Perspectives, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - The Meadows, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Lynch Family reunion programs and printings, Johnny Richard Hedgepeth annual family reunion program, and other miscellaneous family documents, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Note Of Izetta (?): "Lord You Promised To Be A Present Help..." n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Outsider art material, including Jeffrey Williams agreements and correspondence; Bridgewater Gallery miscellany, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Names of outsider artists (cards originally filed with the photoprints), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Letter from Paul Bridgewater to Audrey Kates, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Sketches of living quarters, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 34-40)
  - Drafts of poems, diary fragments, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Drafts of poems, May 7 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Draft of essay; A Christmas Story and diary fragments; Christmas greetings list, Dec. 1976-Jan. 1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Prose fragments, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Notes for an essay on Flaubert's l'Education Sentimentale; other literary notes; miscellaneous prose fragments, ca. 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series III. Datebooks/Diaries/Notebooks
  - Datebooks and address books, and three envelopes of slips of papers with names and addresses: 1975, 1981, c. 1981, 1982, 1983, 1984, 1985, and 1987 (Box 4)
  - Volume: Senior Memories 1965; diary 3/13/1971 - c. 4/25/1972; five folders of enclosures (consisting of ephemera, botanical specimens, found items, and other miscellaneous items and written material pinned, pasted, or otherwise attached to the diary pages, or loose between the sheets); diary 5/4/1972 - 4/12/1974; four folders of enclosures (Box 5)
  - Diary 8/27/1974 - 6/6/1975; two envelopes of enclosures; diary 7/10/1975 - 10/24/1975; one envelope of enclosures (Box 6)
  - Diary 10/26/1975 - 3/18/1976; four envelopes of enclosures (Box 7)
  - Diary 11/15/1975 - 12 1975; one envelope of enclosures; diary 3/20/1976 - 6/19/1976; three envelopes of enclosures (Box 8)
  - Diary 6/26/1976 - 12/29/1976; three envelopes of enclosures; diary Jan.-Feb. 1977 (Box 9)
  - Diary 2/25/1977 - 5/30/1977; one folder of enclosures; diary 6/7/1977 - 11/9/1977 (three folders); four envelopes and one folder of enclosures (Box 10)
  - Diary 11/1/1977 - 4/15/1979; two envelopes and two folders of enclosures (Box 11)
  - Diary 5/18/1979 - 6/26/1980; four envelopes and one folder of enclosures (Box 12)
  - Diary 8/9/1980 - 8/28/1982; one folder and one envelope of enclosures (Box 13)
  - Diary 8/28/1982 - 9/14/1984; two envelopes of enclosures (Box 14)
  - Diary 10/5/1984 - 1/1/1986; two envelopes of enclosures (Box 15)
  - Diary 1/4/1986 - 6/16/1987; one envelope of enclosures (Box 16)
  - Diary 6/28/1987 - 7/12/1988; one envelope of enclosures (Box 17)
  - Diary 7/12/1988 - 9/7/1988; one folder and one envelope of enclosures (Box 18)
  - Photocopies of selected diaries: 6/28/1987 - 1/12/1988 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Photocopies of selected diaries: 1/23/1988 - 7/12/1988 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Photocopies of selected diaries: 7/12/1988 - 9/7/1988 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of selected diaries: 9/18/1988 - 1/9/1989 (Box 35, Folder 4)
- Series IV. Photographic Materials
  - Photoprints: outsider art, works and artists, including Joe Kingsberry, Betty Lou Lynch, Izetta Lynch, Lizzie Burgess, Jerry Cook, Allan Pops Cooper, Temperance Copeland, James Boyce, Herman Bridgers, George Eure, Emily Deloatch, Earl Evans, Nevin Evans, John Fenner, Shayira Gamble, Raymond Coins, Lillah Hedgepeth, Queen Hedgepeth, Vernetta Hedgepeth, n.d. (Box 19-23)
  - Photoprints: family members; black male nudes, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Slides: sheets 1-6, quilts; sheets 7-9, house, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Slides: sheets 1-5, Mr. Persons; sheets 6-17, Burwell; sheet 18, Clyde Jones, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Slides: sheets 1-4, Allen "Pops" Cooper; sheets 4-7, HB/Bridges; sheets 7-9, Jeff Williams; sheets 9-11, W. W.; sheet 12, Henry Davis; sheets 12-16, O. J. Stephenson; sheet 16, J. Cooke; sheets 16-18, Owens, Evans, Kingsberry, Gamble, Boone; sheet 18, Delouth/Ewell; sheets 18-19, Person Furniture, Edward M. Bannister, A. Watford, G. Wiggin; heet 19, miscellaneous unknown; sheets 19-21, miscellaneous thrift shop, unknown, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Slides: sheets 1-7, family, n.d. (Box 28)
  - Slides: sheets 1-2, Spring 1976, "Central Park" (2_"); sheets 3-4, Spring 1976, "Jim's T.V., N.Y.C. 7154"; sheets 5-7, Winter, 1976 "St. Thomas"; sheets 8-9, May-Jun. 1974, "Ocracoke and W. 69th"; sheet 10, Feb. 1974, "69th St, Apt., Michelle Patrick, Desk Film For Filter"; sheets 11-12, Spring 1974, "69th St, Apt., Michelle And Friends"; sheet 13, Feb. 1974, "69th St. Apt. Roof"; sheets 14-15, Aug. 1974, "69th St. Apt. Fruit And Vase"; sheet 16, Winter 1974, "N.Y.C."; sheet 17, Fall 1975, "The Old House, Toby And Blie"; sheet 18, Jan. 1976, "Home"; sheet 19, Spring 1976, "Enfield"; sheet 20, Jan. 1976, "Winter House"; sheets 21-22, Spring 1976, "Blie, Dad, Aunt Henrietta, Uncle Tussie"; sheets 23-24, Spring 1976, "57th St. Siri Melchior"; sheet 25, Spring 1976, "Jim's 71st St. Wanna Fuck"; sheets 26-27, Winter 1976, "Durham *3 Good"; Untitled: sheets 28-29, N.D., Cabin, Male Friend, Rhonda And Friend; N. C.; sheets 30-31, N.D., Lynch And Family, N. C.; sheets 32-33, N.D., cabin and person, N. C.; sheet 34, N.D., White Church, N. C.; sheets 35-36, Jun. 1976, Cats On Sill; sheets 37-38, Jun. 1976, people; sheets 39-40, Nov. 1976, cabin, still life landscape; sheets 41-42, Nov. 1976, cabin landscape; sheet 43, Feb. 1974, N. Y. C., Michelle Patrick; sheet 44, Jan. 1974, miscellaneous still-lifes (Box 29)
  - Slides: sheets 1-14, black male nudes (originally kept in orange bag), n.d. (Box 30)
  - Negatives: folk art, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Negatives: family, also landscapes, n.d. (Box 32)
  - Negatives: nudes, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Family photographs and slides, n.d. (Box 36)
- Series V. Videocassettes
  - Orange bag that contained videos, 1987 (Box 34)
  - Larry Lynch - Outside Art In Izetta House, 6/28/1987, VHS, V-214 (Box 34)
  - Larry Lynch, 6/28/1987, VHS, V-215 (Box 34)
  - For Love Not Money: The Robert Lynch Collection Of Local Art, CBS Cable, Umatic, V-216 (Box 34)
  - Unidentified, Umatic, V-217 (Box 34)